翻译，时间轴，压制：Bolshevik0
Whether Jeremy and Lyoko Warriors were battling ominously named evil viruses
不管是Jeremy和Lyoko小队在对抗邪恶的病毒
or simply navigating the pitfalls of high school,
还是应对现实世界学校里中的陷阱
Code Lyoko struck a chord with audiences of all ages around the world.
Code Lyoko都能引起来自全世界各年龄段的观众共鸣
And is still much-loved to this day.
至今仍深受欢迎
And we've got all the tidbits.
而我们收集到所有相关的花絮
you might not have noticed along with development stories
包括你在追番时没发现的彩蛋
and info on the creators.
以及制作人员的故事
Hey guys, I'm Brendan with Channel Frederator
大家好 我是来自Frederator频道的Brendan
and we have probably more information about French teams
也许我们比你
than you ever knew you wanted.
更了解CL背后的法国制作团队
No really there's a lot of France in this one, guys.
没错 这次确实有很多法国元素
From peta-zoo,
（没听清）
the forces of Xana better watch out.
最好小心Xana的力量
Because we're counting down 107 facts about Code Lyoko.
因为我们现在开始倒数107个关于Code Lyoko的事实
Let's get started.
我们开始吧
Number 1, Code Lyoko is a French animated show
其1 Code Lyoko是法国动画节目
that aired for four years spanning 2003 to 2007.
从2003年到2007年播出了四年
While it was aired in France on two channels France 3 and Canal J
当时它在法国的两个频道France 3和Canal J上播出
many American viewers probably recall watching it on Cartoon Network.
许多美国观众可能会记得自己是在Cartoon Network上观看它
Number 2, while Code Lyoko was on Cartoon Network,
其2 虽然Code Lyoko在Cartoon Network上播出
the show was featured on the channels Miguzi Block
它在频道Miguzi Block播出
which replaced Tsunami during the weekday afternoons.
在工作日下午播出 替代了之前的Tsunami
Number 3, strangely the last seven episodes never aired in the U.S.
其3 在美国 奇怪的是最后七集从未被播出
Instead fans could watch them on Cartoon Network's online video service.
不过 粉丝们可以在Cartoon Network的在线视频服务上观看他们
Unfortunately not many knew about this
不幸的是很多人并不知道有这样的渠道
and were left without a season finale.
而没能看完
Why was the show abruptly taken off?
为啥这档节目会被突然取消
An executive from the company mentioned that
该公司的一位管理提到这一点
he just wasn't a fan of the show himself.
仅仅是因为他不喜欢这个动画
This is why we can't have good things.
这就是为什么我们看不到好动画
Number 4, the show was actually so internationally distributed
其4 实际上这部动画在国际上广为传播
that nearly a hundred and sixty countries aired it.
它曾在近一百六十个国家中放送
It was even a big success in Japan.
甚至在日本也获得了很大的成功
which isn't common for a foreign animated show on the island.
对于引进到日本的外国动画而言 这并不常见
Number 5, Code Lyoko had its origins in an independent student short film
其5 Code Lyoko起源于一部独立的学生短片
from the Gobelins, the school of the image in Paris,
来自巴黎的美术学校Gobelins
made by Thomas Romain and Tania Palumbo while they were students there.
Thomas Romain和Tania Palumbo在上学时制作的这部动画
Titled "Les Enfants font leur cinéma" or "the children make their own movies".
名叫「Les Enfants font leur cinéma」 意思是「孩子们自己制作的电影」
Otherwise known as "Les Enfants".
也被称为「Les Enfants」
The children very striking resemblance to the cast in Code Lyoko.
这些孩子与Code Lyoko中的角色非常相似
Number 6, Les Enfants screened at thea été diffusé au Festival in 2000.
其6 Les Enfants在2000年的法国国际艺术节放映
And gave birth to a new project.
并催生了一个新项目
Antefilms, a French animation studio noticed the short,
法国动画工作室Antefilms注意到了这部短片<del>(察觉)</del>
and reached out to Romain Palumbo,
他们找到了Romain和Palumbo
asking if they would like to work on a new show with the company, Garage Kids.
询问他们是否愿意加入到公司里去制作新的动画 Garage Kids<del>(提案)</del>
Number 7, Garage Kids had a five minute pilot in 2001
其7 2001年 Garage Kids有一个五分钟的试播
and was fully intended to go on as a 26 episodes show.
并打算持续更新下去 成为一个26集的动画
Similar to Code Lyoko,
类似Code Lyoko
the main cast who happened to be the same characters as Code Lyoko,
主要角色也和Code Lyoko相同
thought to save the earth from inside a virtual world.
也是设法从虚拟世界中拯救地球
It also had an overall darker tone.
它的整体风格较为黑暗
Number 8, but the virtual reality and Garage Kids was not Lyoko.
其8 但Garage Kids和它的虚拟世界的设定并不是Lyoko那样
Not quite.
不完全是
注: Xanadu意为世外桃源
It went by the name of Xanadu
它名叫Xanadu<del>(幻想乡)</del>
and was created by scientists who were led by an out-of-control professor.
由失控教授领导的科学家制造
Plagued by monsters, Xanadu would create problems in the real world
受到怪物的困扰 Xanadu会在现实世界中制造问题
that the kids would have to fight against.
而孩子们将不得不与之战斗
Number 9, Xanadu was also much smaller in size.
其⑨ Xanadu的规模也小得多
A floating island supported by electric cables.
只不过是由电缆支撑的漂浮的岛屿
The digital land only had six towers.
虚拟世界只有6个圆塔
As opposed to Lyoko's forty one towers.
而不是Lyoko的41个圆塔
Because they upgraded.
算是升级吧
Number 10, to make up for this, after Xanadu became Lyoko,
其10 为了弥补这一点 在Xanadu变成Lyoko之后
a lot of thought went into redesigning the virtual world,
制作组对重新设计虚拟世界有很多想法
is a large place to explore.
让它变成了一个能探索的巨大空间
Four sectors were added.
增加了四个区
Towers remain smaller and landscapes were simplified.
圆塔保持较小的体积而景观得到简化
吐槽: 还记得前传PartⅠ里05:56处Jeremy对Lyoko的称赞吗
But made more ecologically diverse.
但是场景变得更加生态多样化
Number 11, many have stated that the 3D animation in Xanadu
其11 很多人都认为Xanadu的3D动画
well more detailed wasn't as well rendered as in Code Lyoko.
不如Code Lyoko那样细节丰富
Of course it's important to bear in mind that
当然 有一点很重要
the pilot wasn't intended for viewing outside of Antefilm.
就是试看版仅仅在Antefilm内部播出
That being said others mentioned also that the 2d animation seems smoother.
也有人说它的2D动画更流畅
Number 12, another difference in Garage Kids was that
其12 Garage Kids的另一个不同在于
Odd acted as the story central protagonist.
Odd是故事的主角
As a transfer student
作为转学生
he discovers that Jeremy Yumi and Ulrich are already aware of Xanadu
他发现Jeremy Yumi和Ulrich已经知道Xanadu的事
and the troubles as a whole.
以及他们所面对的麻烦
Though he's wary of virtualization
尽管他对虚拟化有些害怕
he joins the group and helps save the day.
但是他仍然加入了团队 并拯救了世界
Number 13, the kids also retained their abilities outside of Xanadu.
其13 孩子们在现实世界也能使用自己的能力
This was shown by Yumi using telekinesis
在试播片段里 Yumi的心灵遥感验证了这一点
to save Jeremy from a disastrous fall in the Garage kids' pilot.
她把Jeremy从致命的坠落中救了回来
Number 14, oh and did we mention, Ulrich's sword was made of binary code.
其14 我们提到过吗 Ulrich的刀是由二进制编码组成的
That's pretty cool.
很帅
But he also had a more spiffy outfit.
同时他也有一个更好看的装束
Number 15, though we didn't get to see Odd and Yumi's virtual outfits,
其15 尽管我们没有看到Odd和Yumi的虚拟世界形象
damn those Paulo ace（没听清） silhouettes,
该死的剪影
concept art suggests that they were the same as what we got in Code Lyoko.
艺术概念表明 它们与Code Lyoko中的相同
Well we mean that Yumi did have longer sleeves.
不过Yumi确实有更长的袖子
Number 16, because this show is going to follow a linear storyline,
其16 因为这个节目将遵循线性剧情
the executives decided to scrap Garage Kids and turned it into Code Lyoko.
公司的管理决定取消Garage Kids并将其变为Code Lyoko
Unfortunately this also meant that
这也不幸地意味着
they were going to give it a significantly smaller budget.
这个项目将获得一个小得多的预算
Number 17, due to all these changes Romain decided to part from the project.
其17 因为这些变动 Romain决定离开这个项目
However he did work with Palumbo on the literary and graphic Bibles
不过 他确实与Palumbo合作过剧本和动画的策划书
which helped guide Code Lyoko's future.
这些规划了Code Lyoko的未来
Number 18, Palumbo stuck with Code Lyoko for all of its 4 animated seasons
其18 Palumbo参与了Code Lyoko四个季度的动画制作
acting as the creative director during development.
她担任制作组的创意总监
She's also the brain behind many of the characters's designs.
参与设计了许多角色
Number 19, ever said the phrase, "This show feels like french anime".
其19 有人曾说过 「这个动画感觉像法国的」
Well after co-creator Romain left the show he worked on Oban Star Racers.
在联合创始人Romain离开了对Oban Star Racers的制作之后
Ever since then he's been working on anime in Japan.
也就是自那时起 他一直在日本从事动画制作
In that world he's most known for designing Space Dandy's ship, the Aloha Oe.
在那里 他以Space Dandy的飞船Aloha Oe的设计而闻名于世
Number 20, regarding those Bibles we talked about,
其20 关于我们前面谈到的策划书
as is often the case
众所周知
there are many differences between what was planned and what became a reality.
计划赶不上变化
For example, Franz Hopper's backstory was originally supposed to
譬如 最初 Franz Hopper的背景故事应该是这样
feature him as a computer science teacher at the boarding school
他在寄宿学校担任计算机科学老师
One day he stumbled upon the supercomputer instead of creating it.
有一天他偶然发现了超级计算机 而不是现在的设定是创建它
After making Lyoko, Aelita and virtualization
制作了Lyoko Aelita和虚拟化程序之后
he disappeared mysteriously within the digital world.
他在虚拟世界中神秘地消失了
Number 21, in the Bible Xana was supposed to be this supercomputer itself
其21 在策划书中 Xana就是这台超级计算机
instead of just a program.
而不仅仅是一个程序
Deactivating Towers on Lyoko, stabilizing Xana overall.
在Lyoko里锁定圆塔 大致稳定住Xana
And in this version
而且在这个版本里
Xana could only affect what happened at the factory and the school.
Xana只能影响工厂和学校
Number 22, as we know it today
其22 就像我们今天所知道的那样
Code Lyoko officially aired on September 3rd 2003 in France
Code Lyoko于2003年9月3日在法国正式播出
注: 冰灵翻译是小熊怪兽，原文意为泰迪哥斯拉
with Teddy Godzilla.
就是第一集小熊怪兽
About half a year later on April 19th 2004,
大约半年后的2004年4月19日
it aired in the U.S..
它在美国播出
Number 23, that's not to say that Garage Kids was entirely dead.
其23 这并不意味着Garage Kids彻底凉了
To save on costs, three pieces of animation were taken directly from the failed pilot.
为了节省成本 Code Lyoko直接从凉凉的试播中截取了三段动画
Specifically Ulrich, Yumi and Odd's virtualizations.
就是Ulrich Yumi和Odd的虚拟化动画
Number 24, 2 credits stills were also nabbed from the original project.
其24  片尾的两个场景也从原来的项目中获得
The one where the group sits on a bench
Lyoko小队坐在长椅上的场景
and the one where Odd and Jeremy are pushing Ulrich and Yumi towards each other.
以及Odd和Jeremy将Ulrich和Yumi推向彼此的那个场景
Number 25, it shouldn't come as a surprise that the creators and writers all agreed that
其25 意料之中的是 经过制作人员的一致同意
注: 中文译名为电子世界争霸战……
one of the inspirations behind Code Lyoko was Tron.
Code Lyoko背后的灵感之一就是电影Tron
From defeating an evil program to the high speed trails, to the visuals of virtualization.
从邪恶程序的挫败到高速通道的概念 甚至是虚拟化的视觉效果
If you keep a sharp eye open you'll definitely notice the similarities.
如果你仔细观察 你一定会注意到相似之处
Number 26, of course another big influence was the Matrix.
其26 当然 另一个影响到Code Lyoko的电影是黑客帝国
Both Aelita and Neo represent the chosen one.
Aelita和Neo都代表了被选召的孩子
Both stories show machines trying to take over man
这两个故事都描写了试图统治人类的机器
and both have a similar fighting style.
并且战斗风格都很相像
Number 27, not to mention that the Lyoko Warriors boarding school Kadic academy
其27 更不用说那个Lyoko小队所在的寄宿学校Kadic学院了
is based on a real-life school in our own world.
它是基于现实世界的一所学校所构造的
Lycée Lakanal is located in the Earth's descend suburb of Paris.
Lycée Lakanal位于巴黎郊区
Number 28, in fact the name of the school is a reference to the American sci-fi author
其28 实际上这所学校的名字参照了美国科幻作家
Philip K. Dick.
Philip K. Dick
That's K. Dick or when it said quickly, Kadic.
K. Dick说快了以后就变成Kadic了
Number 29,
其29
when you're looking at the pictures of the fake and real school side-by-side
当你并排对比两者的区别
the reference becomes immediately obvious due to how similar they look.
因为这两座学校非常相似 显然说明Kadic是有参照Lycée Lakanal
They even have the same trees out front.
它们的大门外甚至有相同的树
Number 30, the factory was also based on a real location
其30 工厂也有现实的模型
though it has been since demolished.
尽管它现在已被拆除
Originally the real-life structure was a Renault production plant
最初的现实模型是雷诺的生产工厂
located to Boulogne-Billancourt.
位于布洛涅 比扬古
Number 31, it's also evident that
其31 很明显地
Code Lyoko gives quite a few respectful nods to Japanese culture.
不少Code Lyoko的细节致敬了日本文化
Yumi's behavior and home
Yumi的行为和Yumi的家
and many visuals especially in Lyoko itself
特别是Lyoko世界里的视觉效果
just help solidify the reason that so many people called this French anime.
这也是这么多人能认出这部法国动漫的原因
Number 32, Yumi's first outfit clearly depicts this.
其32 Yumi的第一套服装致敬了日本文化
She was a Geisha like kimono, even though the geisha were not Warriors.
她是穿着和服的艺妓 虽然艺妓不是战士
However her outfit is more of a hybrid of kimono types
然而她的服装更像是一种混合的和服类型
rather than that of a traditional geisha.
而不是传统艺伎穿的那种
Still, her slippers and hair are up to standard.
尽管如此 她的木屐和头发都达到了艺妓的标准
Number 33, Yumi's weapon of choice is also not Japanese.
其33 Yumi选择的武器也不日本
注: 根据http://codelyoko.wikia.com/wiki/Pencak_Silat，相对而言，班卡苏拉在法国很流行
One ancient martial art that uses fans in combat is Pencak Silat.
在战斗中使用扇子的古代武术是班卡苏拉自卫术
This is not surprising
这并不奇怪
since it's also the branch of fighting that both Yumi and Ulrich train with.
因为它也是Yumi和Ulrich一起训练的一种武术
However, this is an Indonesian sport entirely.
不过这完全是印尼的一项运动
Number 34, Yumi second outfit is a more representational of traditional ninjas
其34 Yumi第二套服装更像传统忍者
which lends itself better to her super cool style and skills.
这更适合她帅气的风格
Number 35, much like Yumi isn't really a geisha
其35 正如Yumi不是真的艺伎
吐槽:
日本武士虽然持有一长一短两把刀但不代表要同时用……
根据https://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/武士_(日本)，短刀胁差一般只有在长刀损坏时才使用
另外第四季Ulrich也有两把一样长的刀了
Ulrich is a false samurais since he only carries one sword instead of two.
Ulrich也不是真的武士 因为他只带一把刀而不是两把
The symbol on his back is also influenced by Noh masks
他背上的标志也受到般若之面的影响
which were theatrical masks that represented gods and demons.
这是代表神和恶魔的戏剧面具
Number 36, Odd designed at least his second outfit
其36 Odd至少设计了他的第二套装备
and it's personally inspired by the video game he loves called Kungfu Commando.
其设计灵感来自他喜欢的一个叫Kungfu Commando的游戏
Number 37, Aelita has pink hair because Palumbo had dyed hair herself.
其37 Aelita有粉红色的头发 因为Palumbo自己染了头发
It also beckons to the many colorful heads of hair one can find in manga and anime.
可能是受到了动漫中多色头发的影响
Maybe she's based on magical girls.
也许她的原型是魔法少女<del>马猴烧酒</del>
Number 38,
其38
William Dunbar's outfit is based on the 16th century German mercenary soldiers
William Dunbar的装束是基于16世纪的德国雇佣兵
who took to the frontlines in battle for higher payments.
他们为了更高的收入而走上战场
otherwise known as the Doppelsöldner.
也被称为双酬佣兵
Number 39, the two-handed sword he uses, Zweihänder, is the exact type of weapon
其39 他所使用的双手剑Zweihänder是一种真实的武器类型
these historic figures used points for accuracy.
历史上双酬佣兵使用它是因为它的精度更好
Number 40, as one of France's best-known cartoons
其40 作为法国最著名的动画之一
Code Lyoko was given the Prix de l'Export 2006 award for animation.
Code Lyoko被授予2006年度的Prix de l'Export动画奖
This award is given to French properties that become internationally acclaimed.
该奖项是用来授予给那些国际知名的法国产品
Number 41, during its run its French audience also voted that
其41 在动画播放期间 经过法国观众的投票
the show is the best on Canal J which is a pretty terrific prize in and of itself.
Code Lyoko成了Canal J上的最佳节目 这确实是一个了不起的奖项
Number 42, after four seasons the show went on a four-year break
其42 四个季度的动画播出之后 动画停更四年
注: 第五季指Code Lyoko Evolution，Evolution意为进化
until its fifth season was released online
直到第五季在网上发布
on December 19th to 2012 in France and February 28th 2013 on U.S.A. TV
2012年12月19日在法国播出 而2013年2月28日在美国的电视台播出
under the name Code Lyoko Evolutions.
名为Code Lyoko Evolutions
Xana was back, stronger than before.
比以前更强大的Xana回来了
But there was something different about this reboot.
但是这次动画重启有些不同之处
It was live action.
这次是真人剧
While the scenes in Lyoko were still 3D animated,
虽然Lyoko的场景仍然是3D动画
the earth scenes had new human faces.
现实世界的场景则有着新鲜的真人面孔
Number 43, though the 3D animation was highly improved
其43 虽然3D动画被大大改善
it didn't make up for the controversies regarding changes in Code Lyoko Evolutions.
它并没有平息观众对Code Lyoko Evolution其他方面变化的争议
Well fans were a bit bothered by personality tweaks, the revamped outfits
角色的性格调整 服装修改让粉丝们不太满意
and Lyoko and several story changes,
当然这也包括Lyoko的变化和几个故事的更改
the biggest issue came down to casting white actresses for certain characters of color
最大的问题则是让白人女演员扮演肤色不那么白的角色
such as Sissi and Samantha.
如Sissi和Samantha
Number 44, Code Lyoko Evolutions only lasted for a single season,
其44 Code Lyoko Evolution只播出了一个季度
ending with a cliffhanger on December 19th 2013 after 26 episodes.
在播出26集之后 于2013年12月19日以悬念结尾
That's right. Xana is still out there plotting the world's demise, gives us shivers.
没错  Xana仍在企图毁灭世界 让人惴惴不安
Number 45, everybody knows that
其45 大家都知道
Yumi and Ulrich have a complicated romantic relationship.
Yumi和Ulrich有着复杂的恋爱关系
But it's heartwarming to know that
不过 让人很暖心的是
the actors who portrayed them in Code Lyoko Evolutions are actually dating.
在Code Lyoko Evolution中扮演他们的演员 在现实中也在约会
They have super cute instagrams together I'm not lying to you.
他们有超级可爱的instagram动态 是真的
Number 46, Star Wars fans will get a kick out of this one.
其46 星球大战的粉丝会对这个彩蛋感到愉悦<del>偷税</del>
If you pay close attention to Jeremy's computer screen,
如果你仔细观察Jeremy的电脑屏幕
you'll notice some Aurebesh letters.
你会注意到一些Aurebesh字母
What's Aurebesh?
Aurebesh是什么
it's a language that's spoken in Star Wars Episode four, a new hope.
这是在星球大战第4集新的希望中讲到的一种语言
Number 47, this cute Easter Egg isn't just a nod to Ghibli
其47 这个可爱的彩蛋不仅仅是对吉卜力的致敬
but it also acknowledges unique Japanese heritage.
但也认可了这独特的日本特色
If you look at her bed you'll notice that she owns a stuffed Totoro plushie.
如果你注意Yumi的床 你会发现她有个龙猫的毛绒玩具
Number 48, well many believe that
其48 很多人都相信这一点
Franz Hopper's name was a reference
Franz Hopper的名字参照了
to the influential computer scientist Grace Hopper.
有名的计算机科学家Grace Hopper
The writer stated that this was only a coincidence.
编剧说这只是一个巧合
But a good one at least.
算是个不错的巧合
Number 49, many fans know about pick on Yumi week
其49 许多粉丝知道Yumi被钦定的一周这个梗
which consisted of episodes 6 through 10 in season one,
就是第一季的第6至10集
where Yumi is consistently the victim of attacks.
Yumi总是攻击的受害者
What do you got against Yumi, Xana?
Xana你攻击Yumi是图个啥
She's the cool one.
她很酷
She does have a big forehead. I'll give you that.
我会给你她那巨大的额头的
Number 50, in the English voice cast Odd and William are the only Lyoko Warriors
其50 在Lyoko小队的英语配音中 只有Odd和William
that have male actors.
是由男性配音
In French a woman voices Odd as well,
而法语配音中 Odd甚至也由女性配音
making Willian the only Warrior with a male voice actor through and through.
使得William成为唯一一位始终由男性配音的成员
Number 51, because Odd voice was extremely high pitched in the French version,
其51 因为Odd法语配音的音调非常高
a Number of French fans were convinced that he was actually a girl.
许多法国粉丝以为他是个女孩
This included Gulliver Bevernaege who is a huge fan of the show
其中包括Gulliver Bevernaege 他是Code Lyoko的狂热粉丝
and actually went on to play Odd in Evolutions.
而他则在Evolution中扮演Odd
Probably pretty happy to be wrong.
也许Gulliver Bevernaege很高兴自己之前的想法是错的
注: MMORPG全称Massively multiplayer online role-playing games
Number 52, there was almost an MMORPG based on the show
其52 Code Lyoko衍生出一款大型多人在线角色扮演游戏
called Code Lyoko Online.
叫Code Lyoko Online
It was going to be developed by CJ Internet Studios
由CJ Internet Studios开发
and would have included 3D graphics on a full combat system.
该游戏的战斗系统是3D的
Number 53, Moonscoop announced the project in 2008
其53 Moonscoop在2008年宣布了该游戏项目
注: reloaded意为重加载
as part of Code Lyoko Reloaded.
将作为Code Lyoko Reloaded的一部分
A culmination of projects that would continue the franchise after the fourth season.
在第四季结束后 它会延续该系列的高峰
The company later solidified the idea of an MMO in 2010
在2010年发布了游戏开发进展的第一稿之后
注: MMO全称Massively multiplayer online
after releasing first draft displaying progress on the game.
该公司确定了制作大型多人在线游戏的想法
Number 54, CJ Internet created the group and flew to work on the game.
其54 CJ Internet创建了这个团队 并开始制作这个游戏
However, design started to go in a direction away from Code Lyoko's original look,
然而 游戏设计背离了Code Lyoko的原始风格
giving it a more Korean influence.
变得越来越韩国化
Number 55, eventually the game was cancelled in December 2012.
其55 在2012年12月 这个游戏最终取消了
Bankrupting influence.
令人大失所望
Many fans after seeing the drastic changes made to Aelita in the game
许多粉丝在看到Aelita在游戏中发生了巨大变化后
are happy that rather than completely destroying the world of Lyoko.
很高兴 而不是想把这个游戏彻底批判一番
The game was, well, put down.
然而这个游戏鸽了
Number 56, however there is a free multilingual game called IFSCL,
其56 不过现在还有一个免费的多语言游戏称为IFSCL
made entirely by a single fan.
只由一个粉丝完成
Mimicking Jeremy's supercomputer, it allows the player to interact with Lyoko
模仿Jeremy的超级计算机 它允许玩家与Lyoko互动
the way Jeremy did when he and the other Lyoko Warriors battled against Xana.
就像Jeremy和Lyoko小队与Xana作战时那样
Sounds cool.
听起来很不错
Number 57, before the fourth season aired,
其57 在第四季播出前
an official Code Lyoko magazine was released
Code Lyoko官方杂志发布了
which contained comics about our heroes
其中包括Lyoko小队的漫画
Sadly, not enough sold and after three editions, the issues were discontinued
不幸的是 杂志销量有限 而且在三个版本之后 这个杂志停载了
注: 此处的之后只是指现实时间上的，不是说小说的剧情承接动画，小说的剧情和动画是平行的
Number 58, after season 4
其58 在第四季播出后的2009年
the italian publisher Atlantica released four books
意大利出版商Atlantica陆续发布了四本书
注: Chronicles意为编年史
under the name Code Lyoko Chronicles, starting in 2009.
名叫Code Lyoko Chronicles
Number 59,
其59
the books were written and released before the series Code Lyoko Evolution
这些书是在Code Lyoko Evolution系列推出之前编写和发布的
and were intended to finish the series off and fill in the plot holes
并且打算结束整个系列并填补剧情漏洞
that the animation never had time to address.
就是一直以来那些动画挖坑不填的部分
Number 60, pretty strangely for a French TV show,
其60 对于一部法国动画来讲有些奇怪
the books were originally written in Italian.
这些书最初是用意大利语写的
Eventually, the first two books were translated into French in 2010 and 2011.
最终 前两本书在2010年和2011年翻译成法文
Number 61, while the books were never officially translated into English
其61 而这些书的官方英文翻译版从未出版
and the last two were never even translated into French,
而后两本的法语翻译版本甚至到从未出版过
fans took to the Internet and provided their own translations for others to enjoy.
于是 粉丝们在网上提供自己的翻译供他人阅读
Number 62, fans of the show debate
其62 Code Lyoko的粉丝们争辩道
whether Code Lyoko Evolution or Code Lyoko Chronicles are the better capstone
Code Lyoko Evolution和Code Lyoko Chronicles哪个更好
to the beloved adventures journey.
对于受欢迎的Code Lyoko系列而言
On the one hand, the novels stood closer to the Canon of the show
一方面 小说更接近该动画的故事线
and actually give it like an end,
并且最终给出了结局
which is something that Evolution does not do.
而Code Lyoko Evolution则没有做到
On the other hand Evolution can be watched.
另一方面Code Lyoko Evolution可以被观看
Privacy of the media on my guess.
这大概就是传播媒介魅力的秘密吧
Number 63,
其63
however the novels do have some minor differences to the Canon of the series.
然而小说确实与该系列的故事线有一些微小的差异
Most of these changes are just to make more economic storytelling
大部分这些差异只是为了让故事更简洁
but the author also decided to change Aelita's hair from pink to red.
但作者还是决定将Aelita的头发从粉红色变为红色
吐槽: 喵喵喵?
Pretty funny to make a visual change in the medium where you know.
你懂的 某些媒介上进行视觉变化是非常有趣的
You don't actually have to see the characters.
尽管在书本里你看不到角色的形象
Number 64, for a brief period during the writing process
其64 在短暂的剧本写作过程中
William Dunbar was going to be named Orlando.
William Dunbar曾被命名为Orlando
The show's head writer Sophie Decroisette said
动画的主要编剧Sophie Decroisette说过
this idea was pretty quickly abandoned.
这个想法很快就被放弃了
Number 65,
其65
though it never came to pass if the animation had progressed beyond season 4,
有个想法从来没被付诸实施
the idea was to make
尽管以前决定这个主意会在第四季之后实施
William Dunbar a more direct villain, an agent of Xana.
就是William Dunbar是一个更直接的反派 作为Xana的代理人存在
The writers always considered him the darkest of the Lyoko Warriors
编剧人员一致认为他是Lyoko小队中最黑暗的
but they never made him a complete villain.
但William从未成为彻底的恶棍
Looks like season 5 would have been his ill face turn.
看起来第五季曾计划让William彻底黑化
Number 66, even though her father Franz Hoppers' Swiss,
其66 尽管Aelita的父亲Franz Hopper是瑞士人
Sophie also said that Aelita was actually born in the United States.
Sophie还说过Aelita实际上是在美国出生的
U! S! A!
美 利 坚(大声)
Number 67,
其67
though Code Lyoko is intended for an audience between the ages of 9 and 12,
尽管Code Lyoko是为9岁至12岁之间的观众设计的<del>子供番</del>
it is a whole host of older fans.
它的粉丝中也不乏年纪更大的人
The creators totally embrace this.
制作团队也认可这一点
And to tribute it to the cooled cyberpunk universe the show in habits.
并向已经凉了一段时间的赛博朋克风格致敬
Number 68, when it came time to do Code Lyoko Evolution,
其68 在Code Lyoko Evolution制作的时候
two directors were used for the entirety of the show.
雇佣了两位导演
This is an unusual to have multiple directors in television
虽然这在电视节目中是不寻常的
but their work was split down the middle for every episode.
但是每集中都各有一半工作分派给他们
Lucio Di Rosa did the live-action sequences
Lucio Di Rosa负责真人部分
and Florian Ferrier did the 3D animated sequences.
Florian Ferrier负责3D动画部分
Number 69,
其69
according to Lucio Di Rosa the live-action director of Code Lyoko Evolution,
根据Code Lyoko Evolution的真人导演Lucio Di Rosa的说法
each episodes live-action segments took about two days to shoot.
每集真人片段大约需要两天的时间去拍摄
With 26 episodes in the season they shot for a total of 46 days.
这季动画的26集花费了46天去拍摄
Just with the live-action cast.
只是给真人演员拍摄
Number 70, so as you can imagine,
其70 可想而知
the live-action part of the show took a lot of prep work.
Code Lyoko Evolution的真人部分进行了大量的准备工作
18 months were spent on it alone with one year entirely spent in preparation.
花费了总共两年半的时间
The live action sequences had to be completely shot and edited
在开始制作动画之前
before the animation process could take over.
真人表演的序列需要完成拍摄和编辑
Number 71, in 2006 Cards France released a Code Lyoko card game.
其71 2006年Cards France发布了一套Code Lyoko的卡牌游戏
It had 160 cards and was played in a similar fashion to yu-gi-oh.
它有160张牌 玩法和游戏王相似
But was never exported to America.
但从未出口到美国
Sorry guys.
很遗憾
Number 72, America did get a bunch of Code Lyoko video games though.
其72 在美国确实能玩到一堆Code Lyoko的电子游戏
注: Quest for Infinity意为追求无限
Code Lyoko Quest for Infinity was released on the Nintendo Wii in 2007.
Code Lyoko Quest for Infinity于2007年在任天堂Wii上发布
With a PlayStation 2 and PSP version following the next year.
而次年就推出了PS 2和PSP版本
注: Fall of Xana意为Xana的陨落
Code Lyoko the Game and Code Lyoko Fall of Xana
Code Lyoko the Game和Code Lyoko Fall of Xana
were also for the Nintendo DS in the same years.
在同一年也登陆了NDS
Number 73, Code Lyoko Quest for Infinity would set up like an action shooter.
其73  Code Lyoko Quest for Infinity是一个动作射击类游戏
With players using the Wii mode to aim and shoot with the various heroes
玩家在扮演Lyoko角色的同时 使用Wii模式瞄准和射击
注: JRPG全称Japanese role-playing games
while the DS games were much more like JRPGs
而DS游戏更像日式角色扮演游戏
complete with turn-based battle modes and Final Fantasy ethical leveling system.
只有回合制战斗模式和类似最终幻想的升级系统
The Wii game also had the full language voice cast back reprising their roles.
Wii游戏也有对应的角色配音
Sadly for handheld gamers, you had to read data center.
不幸的是 对于掌上游戏玩家 你必须读取数据中心
Number 74, the Wii game allowed for players to jump into the shoes of
其74  Wii上的游戏允许玩家选择这些角色
Odd, Ulrich, Yumi or Aelita.
Odd Ulrich Yumi或Aelita
All of whom had their own abilities and played differently.
每个人的能力不同 玩法不同
Ulrich was close quarters combat.
Ulrich擅长近距离战斗
Odd and Yumi played medium to long range with shooting mechanics
Odd和Yumi则是中长距离射击
and Aelita was purely defensive.
而Aelita纯粹是防守性的
Her special power, levitate over holes.
她的特殊能力是悬浮在洞上
Number 75, if you were looking for collectibles more off the beaten path,
其75 如果你正在寻找收藏品而不是游戏
there were also remote-controlled vehicles of Odd's overboard and Ulrich's overbike
还是有遥控版的Odd的滑板和Ulrich的摩托车可以找到
that you could pick up.
你可以收集这些玩具
They're not manufactured anymore
不过 这些玩具已经停产了
so they're probably pretty valuable collector's items.
所以它们可能是很有价值的收藏品
Number 76, not weird enough for you?
其76 对你而言这些还不够奇怪吗
Spain got an exclusive line of Code Lyoko figurines
Code Lyoko曾在西班牙生产过一套角色手办
ranging up through season four of the show.
有第一季到第四季的版本
They never got exported though.
他们从来没有出口到国外过
So be sure to look for them the next time you're just like.
所以如果你喜欢的话 下次记得找找看
I don't know. Chilling in Madrid or something.
我猜不到你那时的神情是什么 在马德里放松还是什么
You guys remember Spanish from high school right?
你们还记得高中时学会的西班牙语吗
Number 77, one interesting thing about the production of Code Lyoko
其77 关于Code Lyoko制作的一件有趣的事情
was that its creators really cared what the fans were talking about.
就是制作人员真的关心粉丝们在谈论什么
After season one started getting some attraction in France,
从第一季开始 动画在法国获得一些影响力后
the creative team actually started frequenting message boards
制作团队开始频繁地在留言板上提问
to ask fans opinions on what directions they'd like the show to go in.
向粉丝询问关于动画剧情发展方向的意见
Number 78, using a lot of this information,
其78 通过大量的意见
head writer Sophie Decroisette and the series creator Jérôme Mouscadet
主要编剧Sophie Decroisette和系列导演Jérôme Mouscadet
actually went back and changed the series Bible
确实更改了系列策划书
before starting production on season 2.
在第二季开始播出之前
This is a pretty bold move actually
实际上这是一个非常大胆的举动
because in television the series Bible is written before production
因为在电视节目中 系列策划书是在制作之前编写的
and usually remains unchanged throughout the entire run.
并且通常在整个播放过程中保持不变
It supposed to be like a guideline for writers to make the characters consistent
它应该是编剧们使角色保持一致的指导方针
so altering it is a pretty big deal
所以改变它是个大胆的赌局
and shows how much they really cared about making a good show
这说明剧组确实有用心去做好这个动画
that also pleased the fans.
这也让粉丝们感到愉悦<del>偷税</del>
Number 79, big changes from the fans that went into the new series Bible
其79 来自粉丝的建议使得新的策划书产生了巨大变化
included makings Xana's objective a lot clearer,
包括让Xana的目的更为清晰
fleshing out the story of Franz Hopper
充实了Franz Hopper的故事
and actually making Aelita a real human.
并让Aelita成为一个真正的人类
She was originally imagined to just be an AI throughout the show.
最初在整个系列中 她只是被设想成一个AI
Number 80, Sophie Decroisette also wrote the series Bible for Code Lyoko Evolution
其80 Sophie Decroisette还为Code Lyoko Evolution编写了系列策划书
but left before production started.
但在开始制作前离开
In a 2016 interview she said,
她在2016年的一次采访中表示
"I quickly saw that production wanted to be on a particular story level
「我很快发现制作方想要的那种故事层面
that didn't agree with my ideas on the series
和我对这个系列的看法不同
so I quit production."
所以离开了制作组」
Number 81, another way fans influenced the series naming the group.
其81 粉丝以另一种形式影响了这个系列对主角团的命名
People started calling the friends Lyoko Warriors online during season 1.
从第一季开始 人们就在网上将主角团称呼为Lyoko Warriors
And by the time season 3 rolled around Jeremy and the gang
到了第三季 Jeremy和他身边的小团体
had adopted the term themselves.
已经如此称呼自己了
Number 82, for a long time fans have speculated over
其82 很长一段时间内 粉丝都在猜测
what the name of the main series
Code Lyoko整个系列中
villain Xana actually means.
反派Xana的真实目的
Is it a name?
Xana是个名字吗
Is it a French acronym?
Xana是法语的缩写吗
Where did it come from and what does it mean?
它来自哪里 它是什么意思
Turns out the lead writers don't know either.
原来 主要编剧也不知道
When I got there said Sophie Decroisette, "It was already named Xana.
我问过Sophie Decroisette 她说 「它已经被命名为Xana
I don't know why. Perhaps that came from Xanadu."
我不知道为啥 也许这是来自Xanadu」
Number 83, speaking of it. Remember how in Garage Kids
其83 谈到这 还记得Garage Kids里
the world of Lyoko was originally called Xanadu.
Lyoko的世界最初名为Xanadu
Beyond being a mythical reference,
除了神话参考之外
this is also probably taken from anime Serial Experiments Lain.
这也可能取自动画玲音
As the show features a satellite named Xanadu
由于这个动画中出现了名为Xanadu的卫星
which housed all the knowledge of humanity inside of it.
其中蕴藏着人类的所有知识
Number 84, in several episodes of the series it's revealed that
其84 在Code Lyoko中能发现
William Dunbar is afraid of spiders.
William Dunbar对蜘蛛的恐惧
Funny enough when he's possessed by Xana he's often seen riding a tarantula.
有趣的是 当他被Xana控制<del>占有</del>时 能看到他经常骑着狼蛛
Yes, the Xana possession also cures arachnophobia.
是的 Xana的控制也能治愈蜘蛛恐惧症
Number 85, Yumi actually knows Morse code
其85 Yumi实际上知道摩尔斯电码的含义
which she uses to communicate with her brother to keep secrets from her parents.
Yumi用它与她的弟弟Hiroki交流而不让父母知道他们的秘密
Man, I wish I'd thought of that when I was kid.
天哪 我希望我还是个小孩的时候就会想到这点
Number 86, Code Lyoko was of course originally broadcast in French.
其86 Code Lyoko当初是用法语播放的
When it came time to dub the show into English,
在对节目进行英语配音的时候
Moonscoop looked for native English speakers in France,
Moonscoop在法国寻找以英语为母语的人
leading to only about 7 people lending the voices of the entire English cast.
结果是只有大约7人参与整个英语配音
This is probably one of the only instances
这也许是为数不多的几个机会
in which you can get literally paid to talk to yourself for hours.
就是你可以通过好几个小时的自言自语来赚钱
Number 87, the actors who played the live-action Yumi in Code Lyoko Evolution
其87 在Code Lyoko Evolution中扮演Yumi的真人演员
is not actually Japanese.
实际上并不是日本人
Melanie Tran is her name and she is a Vietnamese ancestroarium.
她的名字是Melanie Tran 她是个越南裔
Number 88, it should be mentioned
其88 应该提到
however that Melanie also practices gymnastics at a competitive level
Melanie的体操达到了竞技水平
remind you of a certain Lyoko Warrior.
让你想起某个Lyoko战士
Looks like the casting director did their homework after all.
看起来 选角导演毕竟做了功课
注: 最后通牒是第二季第41集(S2E41)
Number 89, in the episode ultimatum,
其89 在最后通牒那一集中
there's some graffiti in the warehouse that Yumi and Odd are being held.
在Yumi和Odd被关押的仓库里 有一些涂鸦
If you look you can see some that reads "Kilroy was here" in English.
如果所见 你可以看到一行英语的句子「Kilroy was here」
This is an odd obscure reference to an ongoing graffiti joke
这是一个奇怪且晦涩的当代涂鸦笑话
that American soldiers scattered across Europe during World War Ⅱ,
最初是二战期间散布在欧洲的美国士兵画过的类似到此一游的涂鸦
basically the 1940s mean.
也就是20世纪40年代发生的事
"Kilroy was here", scrawlings are still being found across Western Europe to this day.
至今仍能在西欧各地发现「Kilroy was here」这样的涂鸦
Number 90, it's also worth mentioning that
其90 这也值得一提
for a show rated TV-Y7 in America,
对于在美国被评为TV-Y7分级的节目
there were some scenes
有一些Code Lyoko中的场景
that were more risque than American audiences were probably used to.
比美国观众可能习惯的更接近底线
Panty shots,
譬如含有内裤的场景
underwear scenes and sexual innuendoes were not uncommon in the show.
以及含有内衣的场面和性暗示<del>.jpg</del>在节目中并不少见
This is partially because France is, well, less loved by these things
这部分是因为法国不是很在意这种程度的分级
and also because Moonscoop was in charge of the English localization
也因为Moonscoop自己负责英文本地化
as opposed to an external American company.
而不是外包给美国公司
Number 91, that being said there were actually lines that
其91 实际上据说Moonscoop还是有一些底线
Moonscoop wasn't willing to cross.
不会去超越
Numerous scenes changed, even after scripts had been locked.
即使在脚本被锁定后 许多场景也发生了变化
Some times for violence.
有时是因为暴力
But mostly for being well a little too sexy.
但主要还是因为性元素过多
Number 92, most of these two risque most fanfic inspiring scenes that were cut.
其92 这两个最同人最伤风化的场景被剪掉
Involve Odd, 2 choice cuts, him exposing himself to Sissi in season 2 episode 28
都和Odd有关 两个场景被砍 他在第二季第28集在Sissi面前脱个精光
吐槽: UO吹爆！
and him in Yumi's body kissing Ulrich's to give him a taste of his crush.
还有就是在Yumi的身体里亲吻了Ulrich 让他体会了恋爱的滋味
Both of these scenes were eventually self-censored by Moonscoop understandably.
可以理解的是 这两个场景最终遭到了Moonscoop的自我审查
Number 93, in France it's a lot more common for fanfiction
其93 在法国 <del>同人逼死官方</del>
to be done on role-playing forums as opposed to the more singular narrative style
同人创作常在角色扮演论坛上完成 而不是一个人写小说那样单打独斗
which is commonly associated with the term in America.
不像美国人常做的那样
There are many suitable forums
有很多合适的Code Lyoko论坛
still active for Code Lyoko scattered across the internet.
依然活跃在互联网的各个角落
注: 这里播主应该是疯狂吐槽大部分论坛都是法语的
En français.
用法语吗
Vous lis en français, oui?
你用的是法语吗
Number 94, there were actually a lot of changes that were dumb a doubt
其94 随着动画的发展
as the scenes went along.
实际上发生了很多变化
In the original Garage Kids short.
在原来的Garage Kids短片中
For instance the Lyoko Warriors kept their powers in the outside world.
譬如 Lyoko小队在外部世界也能使用能力
Number 95, another change
其95 另一个变化
that was made Ulrich almost had a Dragonball Z styled sci-fi monocle.
则是让Ulrich几乎拥有了一款龙珠Z风格的科幻单片眼镜
Moonscoop evidently wanted to keep things under 9000
Moonscoop显然希望在正式播出的时候
when it came to the actual show.
将事情保持在版权法的控制之下 从而没有做出这样的改变
Number 96, the name Aelita might actually be thanks to russian sci-fi.
其96 Aelita这个名字可能出自俄罗斯科幻作品
There's a famous 1923 novel called Aelita or the decline of Mars
有一部著名的1923年的小说叫Aelita 也称火星的衰落
in which the titular Martian princess falls in love with the Soviet cosmonaut.
其中有名的火星公主爱上了苏联宇航员
The name itself might actually be of Latin origin.
名字来自拉丁语
But it's the book that helped popularize it
但是这本书推广了它
and it's obvious that
这很明显
the Code Lyoko team were fans of forward-looking science fiction.
Code Lyoko的制作团队崇尚未来派科幻小说
Number 97, according to elite 2011 PDF by Moonscoop
其97 根据Moonscoop的精英2011 PDF文件
there were originally plans for another animated continuation after season 4
原本计划在第四季之后再拍动画续篇
which would have had the Lyoko Warriors now in high school.
Lyoko小队将会进入高中
It was tentatively titled Code Lyoko Reloaded
它被临时称为Code Lyoko Reloaded
and eventually transformed into Code Lyoko Evolution.
并最终转化为Code Lyoko Evolution
Number 98, the leaked PDF contains future plot line ideas for all the characters
其98 泄漏的PDF包含所有角色未来的情节思路
where are they at now.
包括他们现在的位置
Well first and foremost, Yumi and Ulrich were officially dating.
首先 Yumi和Ulrich正式约会
Take that unresolved sexual tension, its unrealized Canon.
以解决之前悬而未决的恋爱关系 同样也是没能填补的剧情坑
That means it can't be denied.
这说明这段关系被承认了<del>Ulrich同学拒绝不了</del>
Number 99, other cool bits of information include
其99 其他很酷的信息包括
Jeremy now being a well known hacker,
Jeremy现在是一位知名的黑客
Odd moving into the fine arts studies and maturing up a bit,
Odd进入艺术学校 同时成熟了一点
and William Dunbar getting even more team acts
William Dunbar将参与更多的团队行为
and before after being temporarily corrupted by Xana.
而不是之前暂时性地被Xana控制<del>腐蚀堕落</del>
Number 100, another fun fact that I think
其100 我认为另一个事实也很有趣
he really deserves to know.
值得我们了解
In the PDF, you can clearly see that one of the images for high school.
在PDF中 您可以清楚地看到其中一幅有关高中的图片
William is just Justin Bieber with his face poorly obscured.
William的部分是用了一张模糊的贾斯汀比伯的脸
I honestly cannot describe how happy this makes me.
我无法描述我的喜悦<del>我好兴奋啊.jpg</del>
Number 101, strangely Sissi originally had brown hair, not black.
其101 奇怪的是 Sissi原本是棕色头发 而不是黑色
You can find concept art affaire spotting a more auburn hairdo
你可以找到一张概念图 她的头发更偏红褐色
with that same characteristic Sissi as.
正如Sissi的性格一样
Personally I'm kind of surprised they changed it.
就我个人而言 他们对这个设定的改变让我很惊讶
Because when I watched the show as a kid,
因为当我小时候看这个节目时
I kept thinking she was Yumi's sister,
就一直认为她是Yumi的姐妹
wonder what prompted the transition to black.
想知道是什么促使她的发色变黑
注: 此处纯属播主口胡，根据Wikia http://codelyoko.wikia.com/wiki/Code_Lyoko_Evolution
CLE法国线上播放时间2012.12.19, 法国France 4电视台播放时间2013.01.05-2013.12.19
美国线上播放时间2013.02.28，没有哪个日期能对得上2011.12.19，包括他前面08:42说的时间，所以算下来应该是9-10年时间
第一季法国的播放时间是2003.09.03
Number 102, the last episode of Code Lyoko Evolution aired on December 19th 2011,
其102 Code Lyoko Evolution的最后一集在2013年12月19日播出
giving the franchise about an eight year run.
等于说这个系列持续更新了八年
Not too shabby for some that started as a student film.
对于从学生电影作品起步的动画来讲 不算太差
Number 103, the fan base for Code Lyoko is still alive and well today.
其103 Code Lyoko的粉丝团体今天仍然活跃着
Cosplayers tumblr and those aforementioned fan forums.
Coser 汤不热和上述粉丝论坛
They're also flown about
还在运转
and are very vocal about wanting a reboot or proper continuation.
他们都非常期待这个系列重启或者是适当地延续<del>续命</del>
Heck, they even sent us a ton of requests for this 107.
为了制作这期107个真相S6E8 他们甚至向我们发出了许多请求
So here we are.
所以我们就做出来了
Number 104, one of the biggest anime influences on Code Lyoko
其104 对Code Lyoko影响最大的动画之一
is a groundbreaking 1998 anime series Serial Experiments Lain.
是一部突破性的1998年动漫玲音
Lain is a much darker story.
玲音是一个黑暗得多的故事
Definitely not intended for children
绝对不适合儿童观看
which focuses on the difference
其重点在描绘
between reality in the virtual world
虚拟现实
and how interactions with virtual reality can influence our lives.
和与虚拟现实的互动之间的差异 以及这些如何影响我们的生活
The influence of Lain particular can be seen visually.
玲音的特别影响可以在视觉上发现
In the colour palette and the design of the computers in Code Lyoko.
Code Lyoko的调色和电脑的设计与玲音类似
Heck, Jeremy's computer setup after a while is more or less Lain's room.
哎呀 Jeremy电脑房间的布置或多或少都参照了玲音的房间
Number 105, another similarity between Lain and Code Lyoko
其105 玲音和Code Lyoko之间的另一个相似之处
is the appearance of the men in black who pursue Aelita.
则是追查Aelita的黑衣男子
In the other series there are actually two, well, men in black suits
在玲音中 实际上有两名穿着黑色西装的男士
who monitor and hunt the main character Lain.
监视和抓捕主角玲音
While in Lain, they ultimately aren't there to capture her.
而在动画里 他们最终没能抓住她
Their appearance is no less sinister or creepy.
他们的外表总是令人毛骨悚然
Number 106, also while we're at it.
其106 我们差不多也快结束了
Logos on computers are the same.
电脑上的徽标是相同的
Lain and Aelita are both a virtual presence that takes on a physical form eventually.
玲音和Aelita设定上一开始都是虚拟的存在 而最后实体化
Both series have over use of mysterious acronyms
这两个系列都使用了神秘的首字母缩略词
to describe computer viruses and green glowy text and on and on and on.
用来描述计算机病毒 以及绿色的发光文本等等
Let's just leave it at this.
先谈到这儿
Code Lyoko took a lot of influence from Lain.
Code Lyoko受到了玲音的很多影响
And the reason I'm telling you about it
我告诉你的原因
is if you were a fan of the show back in the day,
则是如果你当年看过Code Lyoko
Serial Experiments Lain is well worth checking out now that you're older.
那么现在值得补一下玲音这个番 因为你年纪大了
Go get lost in the wired my friends.
朋友们 迷失在连线中吧
Don't feel bad if you have to look up explanations online afterwards.
如果你看后必须要在网上查找相关解释 <del>要有宽容の心</del> 不要觉得不爽
Number 107, so when you are watching Code Lyoko on Cartoon Network,
其107 所以当你在Cartoon Network上观看Code Lyoko时
you might have been forgiven for thinking it was an American show.
你可能曾因为误认为这是一场美国动画而被原谅
Or maybe a Japanese one or something.
或者错认成日本动画 或者别的什么
Probably not France.
总之很难认成法国动画
You know, it's another anime influence show
你知道 这是另一个受动漫文化影响的动画
you probably weren't aware with secretly French.
你可能没有意识到它是「神秘地」由法国人制作
Totally spies.
可以说是藏得很深了
No joke. If you didn't watch it, honestly you missed out.
不是开玩笑 如果你没有看过 你肯定很遗憾
That's sure rocked.
Code Lyoko让人印象深刻
Well, that's about it for me and the Lyoko Warriors.
这期节目差不多就是这些
I'm Brendan and thanks for watching 107 facts about Code Lyoko.
我是Brendan 并感谢您收看有关Code Lyoko的107个事实
Who's your favorite character?
谁是你最喜欢的角色
Did we miss anything?
我们错过了什么吗
What's up with France?
法国怎么样
Comment below and let us know
到油管去评论 让我们知道
and don't forget to click the bell to become part of the notification squad.
不要忘记订阅我们频道以便收到通知
We got new videos dropping every day so make sure to subscribe.
我们每天都会上传新视频 因此请确保订阅
Because remember Frederator loves you, blahblahblah.
记住 我们如此勤劳是因为我们频道爱你 blahblahblah